<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SIGHPC Education Working Committees on AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/</link><description>Recent content in SIGHPC Education Working Committees on AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Awards Committee</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/awards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/awards/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="committee-description">Committee Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The awards committee is responsible for coordinating, revewing and selecting the bi-annual SigHPCEdu award to recognize outstanding contributions to computational, data-enabled science, and HPC education and training in all disciplines.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2024-committee">2024 Committee&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>2024 committee consists of the following members.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dirk Colbry colbrydi[at].msu.edu&lt;br>
Linda Akli lakli[at]tacc.utexas.edu &lt;br>
Juana Moreno moreno[at]lsu.edu&lt;br>
Aaron Weeden aaronwee[at]buffalo.edu &lt;br>
Weronika Filinger w.filinger[at]epcc.ed.ac.uk&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="volunteer-opportunities">Volunteer Opportunities&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A new committee is selected every two years. To join a future SigHPCEdu committee please send an email to the SigHPCEdu chair.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Computational Science Education Committee</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/computational-science-education/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/computational-science-education/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="committee-description">Committee Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This committee will be responsible for developing strategies to incorporate and/or enhance computational science education at all levels of education.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The committee will explore education programs and instructional materials for computational and data science across the curriculum. This committee is charged with making available educational material relating to computational science and High Performance Computing. To accomplish this, the committee has assembled and maintains a list of related educational resources They also work with the Outreach Committee to identify and promote reviews of education and training content through webinars and chapter blog.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>K-12 Education Committee</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/k12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/k12/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="committee-description">Committee Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The purpose of the SIGHPC Education K-12 Committee is to support educators introducing HPC &amp;amp; Data Science concepts in K-12 settings by:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Building community and connecting people working in this space&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Identifying and promoting useful teaching resources and activities, aligned with the discipline standards, including Math &amp;amp; Science (and relevant standards from other countries.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Supporting professional development for both in-service and pre-service teachers, particularly in the Computational Thinking and Parallel Thinking spaces&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Identifying gaps in the existing resources and supporting the development of new resources to fill those gaps.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Identifying funding and resource opportunities to support these activities&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="committee-goals">Committee Goals&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In coordination with the education content committee, develop pathways in Data Science and HPC education at the K-12 level to best prepare students to advance their undergraduate studies.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Build career identification resources for K-12 to demonstrate the application of these skills&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Identify resources directly relevant to the K-12 (pre-college) charter, which may then be proposed for addition to the repository of resources for K-12 education in HPC and Data Science.
Support and advocate for pre-service teacher training in Computational and Data Science.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Seek partnerships with appropriate teacher professional associations around the world.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="volunteer-opportunities">Volunteer Opportunities&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Review and update the contents of the K-12 education resources repository&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Conduct of survey of HPC centers to document their programs for pre-college students and teachers&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Outreach Committee</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/outreach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/outreach/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="committee-description">Committee Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The outreach committee is responsible for arranging and promoting a variety of communications mechanisms for the Chapter. This includes promotion of workshops via the Chapter website, email, social media, and other communications outlets. The committee also sees volunteers to provide webinars on a variety of HPC education and training topics, posts to the Chapter blog, presentations at professional meetings, and short videos on training topics.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="committee-goals">Committee Goals&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Promote the chapter&amp;rsquo;s education goals through webinars, blog posts, and social media&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Maintain communication channels through announcements of chapter events and activities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Solicit participation in webinars, blog additions, and other communication channels&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="join-the-committee">Join the Committee&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We welcome participation in committee activities in several ways. You can choose to volunteer to start one of the projects in the activities folder linked below. You can also join the committee to help oversee all of the outreach activities. To do either of these or just to get more information, please contact the committee chair.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Systems Professionals Committee</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/systems-professionals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/systems-professionals/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="committee-description">Committee Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This committee is charged with curating, recommending and making available material and resources addressing topics of interest to the HPC systems professionals.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Beyond technical topics of interest this committee is charged with the identification and promotion of materials geared towards initial entry and professional development of the wide range of professionals who help to manage HPC systems.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To accomplish this, the committee will work with other committees to leverage existing efforts in technical infrastructure, communications and outreach work and other efforts.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="committee-goals">Committee Goals&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The committee will develop a process through which members can add material to a repository, and prepare materials for workshops and webinars. The Systems Professionals Committee of the SIGHPC Education Chapter has assembled a list of training resources for systems professionals. In the the future, we also expect to include reviews of the materials.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Workshop Committee</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/workshop/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="committee-description">Committee Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The SIGHPC Workshop Committee has its mission promoting the interest in and knowledge of applications of High Performance Computing (HPC) by organizing, coordinating and managing in-person and virtual events and workshops. We are actively engaged in fostering collaborations between all HPC Community members at all education levels in the scientific and big data applications domain, and in facilitating a global forum for HPC and non-HPC members interaction, and in promoting opportunities for members to expand their knowledge of high performance computing.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>