<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ACM SigHPC Education Chapter on AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/</link><description>Recent content in ACM SigHPC Education Chapter on AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://sighpceducation.acm.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About the ACM SigHPC Education Chapter</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/about/</guid><description>The SIGHPC Education chapter has as its purpose the promotion of interest in and knowledge of applications of High Performance Computing (HPC) and computational science. Join us in our efforts to promote computational science and HPC training and education by:
Participating in our webinars and workshops, highlighted on our events pages Volunteer to work with one of our standing committees to provide leadership and coordination of events, training and education activities and resources for the community Use our pointers to training and education materials to find resources that help to update your skills and knowledge Learn from and contribute to our blog on computational science education and training Our goals Promote an increased knowledge of, and greater interest in, the educational and scientific aspects of HPC and their applications.</description></item><item><title>Magic Castle - Terraforming the cloud to teach HPC</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/magic_castle/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/magic_castle/</guid><description>SIGHPC Education Webinar Magic Castle - Terraforming the cloud to teach HPC Are you new to the world of HPC and are trying to find an affordable and accessible way that you can learn, practice and experiment? Do you miss the days when learning about HPC was connecting a few gray boxes together and configuring a cluster? Do you wish you could transfer all the complexity inherent in production HPC systems into an accessible sandbox environment, designed to facilitate teaching and experimental development?</description></item><item><title>SIGHPC Education Annual Meeting 2024</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/annual24/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/annual24/</guid><description>SIGHPC Education Annual Meeting 2024 Materials from the annual meeting on January 9 at 10:00 AM Eastern Standard Time.
Meeting video
Presentation slides</description></item><item><title>SEHET23 Technical Progam</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/sehet_23_tech/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/sehet_23_tech/</guid><description>Sixth Workshop on Strategies for Enhancing HPC Education and Training (SEHET23) Technical Program Monday July 24, 2023
Time: 8:30 AM - 11:30 AM (PST)
08:30 AM-8:45 AM
Welcome SIGHPC Education Chapter
Nitin Sukhija, Slippery Rock University of Pennsylvania
8:45 AM -10:45 AM
Paper Session
8:45 AM -9:00 AM
&amp;ldquo;Assessing Shared Material Usage in the High Performance Computing (HPC) Education and Training Community&amp;rdquo;. Susan Mehringer, Katharine Cahill, Charlie Dey, Scott Lathrop, J-P Navarro, Jeaime Powell and Mary Thomas</description></item><item><title>Three years of the ARCHER2 training service</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/archer2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 01:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/archer2/</guid><description>SIGHPC Education Global Seminar Series - Three years of the ARCHER2 training service - a retrospective and forward look Juan Rodriguez Herrera
Thursday, June 8
16:00 BST
11:00 AM EDT
YouTube Video
Abstract The ARCHER2 training service started in April 2020 with an online programme of courses and virtual tutorials. EPCC, as part of the ARCHER2 UK National service, deliver a training programme that covers a wide range of scientific disciplines and technology platforms, and addresses the training requirements of users with different needs and level of experience.</description></item><item><title>SIGHPC Education Global Seminar Series - Africa 1</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/africa1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 10:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/africa1/</guid><description>SIGHPC Education Global Seminar Series - Africa 1 Bryan Johnston, Binjamin Barsch
Friday, March 31 2023 at 08:30 AM EDT
YouTube Video Presentation Slides: Talk #01 | Talk #02 Chat Transcript Abstract Talk 1: Towards Sustainable HPC Workforce Development for the HPC Ecosystems Community in Africa The HPC Ecosystems Project is responsible for the distribution and deployment of HPC Systems in Africa, as well as HPC Personnel training related to these systems.</description></item><item><title>Computational Physics Webinar - Computational Physics in the Classroom</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/physicsclass/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 10:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/physicsclass/</guid><description>Computational Physics Webinar - Computational Physics in the Classroom David Joiner, Rubin Landau, Robert Panoff, Richard Gass
Wednesday, April 5 at 1:00 PM EDT.
YouTube Video Presentation Slides: Talk #01 | Talk #02 | Talk #03 Abstract Presenters will discuss various aspects of integrating computational physics into the classroom
Running classroom 3D Physics simulations with visualization in Unity Game Engine (David Joiner) Many Body for Anybody (Robert Panoff) Some CP Topics that Should be Taught, but Usually Aren&amp;rsquo;t (Rubin Landau) The session was moderated by Richard Gass</description></item><item><title>EESSI - A streamed, production-quality, multi-platform HPC software stack</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/eessi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/eessi/</guid><description>EESSI: A streamed, production-quality, multi-platform HPC software stack Dr. Alan O&amp;rsquo;Cais and Kenneth Hoste
Wednesday, January 25 at 10:00 AM ET.
YouTube Video
Presentation Slides
Abstract The European Environment for Scientific Software Installations EESSI project aims to provide a ready-to-use stack of production-quality scientific software installations that can be leveraged easily on a variety of platforms, ranging from personal workstations to cloud environments and supercomputer infrastructure, without making compromises with respect to performance.</description></item><item><title>BPHTE23 Call for Papers</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte23cfp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte23cfp/</guid><description>BPHTE23 CFP Call for Papers Tenth SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education (BPHTE23)
November 12-17, 2023
Held in conjunction with SC23: The International Conference on High Performance Computing, Networking, Storage, and Analysis
https://sc23.supercomputing.org/
Since 2014, the Best Practices for HPC Training workshop series at SC has provided a global forum for addressing common challenges and solutions for enhancing HPC training and education, for sharing information through large and small group discussions, and for fostering collaboration opportunities.</description></item><item><title>Second Workshop on Strategies for Enhancing HPC Education and Training Curriculum - SEHET19</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/sehet19/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/sehet19/</guid><description>Second Workshop on Strategies for Enhancing HPC Education and Training PEARC Conference, Chicago, IL, July 28 - August 1, 2019 Presentation Slides</description></item><item><title>Educational Award For Outstanding Contribution to Computational Science Education</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/award_announce/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/award_announce/</guid><description>ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter Educational Award For Outstanding Contribution to Computational Science Education The ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter is pleased to announce the first recipient of the Educational Award for Outstanding Contribution to Computational Science Education Dr. Robert M. Panoff.
Dr. Robert Panoff is noted for his work assisting faculty with the integration of computational science into the undergraduate curriculum. Dr. Panoff also collected and distributed curricular materials as exemplars for adoption in the curriculum.</description></item><item><title>Sixth SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education - BPHTE19</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte19agenda/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte19agenda/</guid><description>Sixth SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education - BPHTE19 Sunday November 17, 2019
Time: 9 AM - 5:30 PM
09:00 PM-09:20 AM
Welcome SIGHPC Education Chapter
Nitin Sukhija, Slippery Rock University of Pennsylvania
Scott Lathrop, University of Illinois
Julia Mullen, Massachusetts Institute of Technology
Nia Alexandrov, Daresbury Laboratory, Sci-Tech Daresbury
9:20 AM -12:30 PM
Paper Session I: (Chair: Scott Lathrop)
09:20 AM -09:40 AM
FreeCompilerCamp.org: Training for OpenMP Compiler Development from Cloud.</description></item><item><title>Third Workshop on Strategies for Enhancing HPC Education and Training (SEHET20)</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/sehet20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/sehet20/</guid><description>Third Workshop on Strategies for Enhancing HPC Education and Training (SEHET20) at PEARC20 SEHET20_Technical_Program</description></item><item><title>March 2020 SIGHPC Education Chapter Update</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/update2020-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/update2020-3/</guid><description>March 2020 SIGHPC Education Chapter Update Monday March 16, 11 AM Eastern Time YouTube Video Presentation Slides</description></item><item><title>Mentoring Maximize Your Impact</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/mentoring_webinar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/mentoring_webinar/</guid><description>Mentoring Webinar
Mentoring: Maximize Your Impact Sally Ellingson, Sarvani Chadalapaka, Jay Lofstead, and Julian Kunkel
Wednesday, November 6 at 12:00 PM ET.
YouTube video
Mentoring has the potential for great impact, and can play a key role in building community and bringing new researchers to HPC. However, sometimes getting involved in mentoring can be intimidating, and it can be difficult to find best practices for mentoring in HPC. In this webinar, &amp;ldquo;Mentoring: Maximize Your Impact&amp;rdquo;, four panelists with extensive mentoring experience will share their perspectives on effective mentoring, their own experiences, and tips on how to organize your mentoring program, followed by discussion and Q&amp;amp;A.</description></item><item><title>Overview of the 2019 Outreach Activities of the IEEE Technical Consortium on High Performance Computing</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/ieee/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/ieee/</guid><description>Overview of the 2019 Outreach Activities of the IEEE Technical Consortium on High Performance Computing Presentation Slides YouTube Video</description></item><item><title>Using flipped classroom and Jupiter Notebooks to teach undergraduates parallel programming</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/flipped/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/flipped/</guid><description>Using flipped classroom and Jupiter Notebooks to teach undergraduates parallel programming YouTube Video</description></item><item><title>Webinar - Choosing Accessible Conferencing and Chat Platforms</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/accessible/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/accessible/</guid><description> Choosing Accessible Conferencing and Chat Platforms Friday November 6, 2020 at 3:00 PM ET YouTube Video Chat contents with related links</description></item><item><title>Webinar - Doing more with Google CoLab - CUDA Programming and beyond</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/annual20/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/annual20/</guid><description> Annual Meeting and Member Update 2020 Tuesday, December 1, 9 AM ET YouTube Video Presentation Slides</description></item><item><title>Webinar - Doing more with Google CoLab - CUDA Programming and beyond</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/colab/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/colab/</guid><description> Webinar: Doing more with Google CoLab: CUDA Programming and beyond Thursday, March 17, 2022 11 AM EDT YouTube Video Presentation Details</description></item><item><title>Webinar - Incorporating High Performance Computing in a Physics Curriculum</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/physics1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/physics1/</guid><description>Webinar - Incorporating High Performance Computing in a Physics Curriculum Tuesday September 15, 2020 at 10:00 AM ET YouTube Video Presentation Slides</description></item><item><title>Webinar - Integrating Computational Science into the Chemistry Curriculum</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/chem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/chem/</guid><description>Integrating Computational Science into the Chemistry Curriculum Friday March 6, 2020 3 PM Eastern Time YouTube Video</description></item><item><title>Webinar - Introducing Computational Science in the Undergraduate Physics Curriculum</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/physics2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/physics2/</guid><description>Introducing Computational Science in the Undergraduate Physics Curriculum Session 1: Thursday, November 14, 2019 YouTube Video Session 2: Friday, December 6, 2019 YouTube Video Presentation 1 Presentation 2</description></item><item><title>Webinar - Student Simulations of Local Wildfires in a Liberal Arts Geography Course</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/wildfire/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/wildfire/</guid><description>Student Simulations of Local Wildfires in a Liberal Arts Geography Course Thursday, January 27, 2022 11 AM ET YouTube Video</description></item><item><title>Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education - Agenda</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/sc19/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/sc19/</guid><description>Agenda - Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education BPHTE19 Agenda</description></item><item><title>Membership</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/membership/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 14:18:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/membership/</guid><description>group Join the SigHPC Education ACM Chapter Chapter membership is open to anyone with an interest in High Performance Computing (HPC) education. Chapter members do not need to be members of ACM or enrolled with an educational institution
Membership is $10 for professionals and $5 for students and you can join at this location: Membership Application. Once you have joined, you will be on our email list to receive notices of activities and events.</description></item><item><title>BPHTE22 Call for Papers</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte22/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte22/</guid><description>BPHTE22 CFP Call for Papers
Ninth SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education (BPHTE22)
November 13-18, 2022
Held in conjunction with SC22: The International Conference on High Performance Computing, Networking, Storage, and Analysis
https://sc22.supercomputing.org/
Since 2014, the Best Practices for HPC Training workshop series at SC has provided a global forum for addressing common challenges and solutions for enhancing HPC training and education, for sharing information through large and small group discussions, and for fostering collaboration opportunities.</description></item><item><title>Events 2018 and Prior</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/pre2018/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/pre2018/</guid><description>Events from 2018 and Earlier OpenMP: An Industrial Strength On-Node Programming Model
Monday January 7, 2018 11 AM Eastern Time Webinar Video Extending Computational Training Using Informal Means
Tuesday, December 4, 2018 - YouTube Video Fifth SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education
The Morgan Teaching to Increase Diversity in STEM (MTIDES) Project
YouTube Video Introducing the HPC Certification Program
Presentation Slides YouTube Video Trends and Strategies in Advanced Research Computing Education</description></item><item><title>SEHET20 Technical Program</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/sehet20_technical_program/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/sehet20_technical_program/</guid><description>Third Workshop on Strategies for Enhancing HPC Education and Training (SEHET20)
Monday July 27, 2020
Time: 1:00 PM - 5 PM (PST)
01:00 PM-1:20 PM
Welcome SIGHPC Education Chapter
Nitin Sukhija, Slippery Rock University of Pennsylvania
1:20 PM -3:00 PM
Paper Session
1:20 PM -1:40 PM
&amp;ldquo;Ask.Cyberinfrastructure.org: Creating a Platform for Self-Service Learning and Collaboration in the Rapidly Changing Environment of Research Computing&amp;rdquo;. Julie Ma, Torey Battelle, Katia Bulekova, John Goodhue, Aaron Culich and Jacob Pessin</description></item><item><title>SEHET22</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/sehet22/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/sehet22/</guid><description>Fifth Workshop on Strategies for Enhancing HPC Education and Training (SEHET22)
Monday July 11, 2022
Time: 8:30 AM - 11:30 AM (EST)
08:30 AM-8:45 AM
Welcome SIGHPC Education Chapter
Nitin Sukhija, Slippery Rock University of Pennsylvania
8:45 AM -10:45 AM
Paper Session
8:45 AM -9:00 AM
&amp;ldquo;The Multi-Tier Assistance, Training, and Computational Help (MATCH) project, a Track 2 NSF ACCESS Initiative&amp;rdquo;. Shelley Knuth, Julie Ma, Alan Chalker, Ewa Deelman, Layla Freeborn, VikrAM Gazula, John Goodhue, JAMes Griffioen, David Hudak, Andrew Pasquale and Mats Rynge</description></item><item><title>SIGHPC Education Chapter Annual Meeting</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/annual22/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/annual22/</guid><description>SIGHPC Education Chapter Annual Meeting Come join us for our annual chapter meeting! This is a great opportunity to interact with chapter leadership, learn about ongoing projects, and help us shape our priorities for the upcoming year.
Thursday, December 8, 10-11 am EST
Post-meeting notes and presentation archive Meeting recording Meeting chat transcript Meeting notes Jamboard Chapter presentation Committee presentations Outreach committee Computational science education committee K-12 committee SYSPROS committee Workshop committee</description></item><item><title>BPHTE20 Technical Program</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte20_technical_program/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte20_technical_program/</guid><description>Tenth SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education BPHTE23 Wednesday November 11, 2020
Time: 10 AM - 6:30 PM (EST)
10:00 PM-10:15 AM
Welcome SIGHPC Education Chapter
Nitin Sukhija, Slippery Rock University of Pennsylvania
10:15 AM -12:00 PM
Session I: (Chair: Scott Lathrop)
10:15 AM -10:30 AM
DeapSECURE Computational Training for Cybersecurity Student: Improvements, Mid-Stage Evaluation, and Lessons Learned. Purwanto, He, Ossom, Zhang, Zhu, Arcaute, Sosonkina, Wu</description></item><item><title>By-Laws</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/bylaws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/bylaws/</guid><description>The SIGHPC Education chapter is the first ACM virtual Chapter. As such, we have devised a set of by-laws that reflects the fact that our membership will be widely distributed geographically and will participate in many of our activities remotely using Internet technologies.
By-laws of the Special Interest Group on High Performance Computing Education Association for Computing Machinery (SIGHPC Education ACM) Chapter. Chartered: May 9, 2014 Article I: Name and Scope This organization shall be called: SIGHPC Education ACM Chapter.</description></item><item><title>Computational Science Education Committee</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/computational-science-education/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/computational-science-education/</guid><description>Committee Description This committee will be responsible for developing strategies to incorporate and/or enhance computational science education at all levels of education.
The committee will explore education programs and instructional materials for computational and data science across the curriculum. This committee is charged with making available educational material relating to computational science and High Performance Computing. To accomplish this, the committee has assembled and maintains a list of related educational resources They also work with the Outreach Committee to identify and promote reviews of education and training content through webinars and chapter blog.</description></item><item><title>Computational Science Resources</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/resources/compsciresources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/resources/compsciresources/</guid><description>General Resource Name Type Interactive Science and Math Simulations Web Applets National Science Digital Library Computational Science Education Repository Petasale Education Modules Catalog Repository Petasale Education Modules - Undergraduate Repository Computational Science Education Reference Desk Repository Programming on Parallel Machines Textbook Open Encyclopedia of Parallel Algorithmic Features Textbook Specific Disciplines Resource Type Physics and Math Applets Applets Physics Laboratory Instructions Repository Shodor Model Example &amp;amp; Tools Repository - Chemistry, Biology. Math Economics Agent Models Repository Virtual Physics Laboratory Forum Computational Chemistry for Chemistry Educators Repository</description></item><item><title>Educational Award For Outstanding Contribution to Computational Science Education</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/award24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/award24/</guid><description>The ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter is announcing an upcoming call for nominations for the 2024 education award to recognize outstanding contributions to computational, data-enabled science, and HPC education and training in all disciplines.
The call for nominations will be issued in March, 2024 with a deadline for submissions on May 31 2024.
We are seeking candidates who have led projects or programs that have made significant contributions to computational science education defined broadly to include all disciplines and all education levels.</description></item><item><title>HPC Resource Links</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/resources/hpcresources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/resources/hpcresources/</guid><description>Getting Started Resource Name Type Oklahoma University Center for Education and Research Workshops Software Carpentry: Basic Skills for Research Computing Web training Matlab_Octave Tutorial Basics - Supercomputing Portal Repository and Links ARCHER-UK National Supercomputing Service Online Training Repository Everyone Resource Name Type U Illinois Computational Science and Engineering Workshops Software Carpentry - Basic Skills for Research Computing Web Training Data Carpentry Web Training HPC Carpentry Web Training The Art of HPC Web Training MIT LLSC-Supercloud Teaching Examples Hands-on Examples in Jupyter Notebooks HPC Univeristy Training Resources Repository of resources XSEDE Online Training Catalog Repository Novice and Intermediate Resource Name Type MPI Tutorial Tutorial VISIT Visualization Tutorial Tutorial Paraview Visualization Tutorial Tutorial parallel Matlab-parallelOctave Tutorial 2016 Argonne Training Program on Extreme Computing -ATPESC Tutorial Supercomputing Portal -Basics Repository and Links Supercomputing Portal - Development Repository and Links Supercomputing Portal - Debugging Repository and Links Supercomputing Portal - Visualization Repository and Links CINECA-SCAI Online Training Repository CINECA-SCAI Training Slides Repository ARCHER-UK National Supercomputing Service Virtual Tutorials Repository ARCHER-UK National Supercomputing Service Online Training Repository Pawsey Supercomputing Centre User Training Material Repository Petasale Education Modules Catalog Repository Petasale Education Modules - Undergraduate Repository Code Vault for HPC Code Samples Repository Introduction to Visualization Repository Open Encyclopedia of Parallel Algorithmic Features Textbook Intermediate and Advanced Resource Name Type NERSC Online Tutorials Tutorial Large Data Visualization Tutorial HPC Textbook and Parallel Programming Book Book Parallel Programming in MPI and OpenMP Book Programming on Parallel Machines Textbook</description></item><item><title>K-12 Education Committee</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/k12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/k12/</guid><description>Committee Description The purpose of the SIGHPC Education K-12 Committee is to support educators introducing HPC &amp;amp; Data Science concepts in K-12 settings by:
Building community and connecting people working in this space Identifying and promoting useful teaching resources and activities, aligned with the discipline standards, including Math &amp;amp; Science (and relevant standards from other countries. Supporting professional development for both in-service and pre-service teachers, particularly in the Computational Thinking and Parallel Thinking spaces Identifying gaps in the existing resources and supporting the development of new resources to fill those gaps.</description></item><item><title>Outreach Committee</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/outreach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/outreach/</guid><description>Committee Description The outreach committee is responsible for arranging and promoting a variety of communications mechanisms for the Chapter. This includes promotion of workshops via the Chapter website, email, social media, and other communications outlets. The committee also sees volunteers to provide webinars on a variety of HPC education and training topics, posts to the Chapter blog, presentations at professional meetings, and short videos on training topics.
Committee Goals Promote the chapter&amp;rsquo;s education goals through webinars, blog posts, and social media Maintain communication channels through announcements of chapter events and activities Solicit participation in webinars, blog additions, and other communication channels Join the Committee We welcome participation in committee activities in several ways.</description></item><item><title>SC2023 Education Activities</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/sc23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/sc23/</guid><description>Listings of HPC education workshops, talks, and BOFs at SC23.</description></item><item><title>SigHPC Education Chapter Officers</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/contact/officer-requirements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/contact/officer-requirements/</guid><description>SIGHPC Education Chapter Officers Volunteerism is the key component to the continued success of our SigHPC Education Chapter. We encourage SIGHPC members to consider serving as a chapter officer. Nominations and applications for officers will be conducted each year and must be submitted around mid-April. The officers shall be elected by a plurality of the votes cast at the annual election, to be held towards the end of April. New officers will take office in May and serve for one year.</description></item><item><title>Systems Professional Resources</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/resources/systems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/resources/systems/</guid><description>The Systems Professionals Committee of the SIGHPC Education Chapter had assembled a list of training resources for systems professionals. In the the future, we also expect to include reviews of the materials. Please provide additional information for this resource listing.
Linux Cluster Institute Oklahoma University Virtual Residency Introductory/Intermediate Workshops Los Alamos National Laboratory Information Science and Technology Institute ISTI</description></item><item><title>Systems Professionals Committee</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/systems-professionals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/systems-professionals/</guid><description>Committee Description This committee is charged with curating, recommending and making available material and resources addressing topics of interest to the HPC systems professionals.
Beyond technical topics of interest this committee is charged with the identification and promotion of materials geared towards initial entry and professional development of the wide range of professionals who help to manage HPC systems. To accomplish this, the committee will work with other committees to leverage existing efforts in technical infrastructure, communications and outreach work and other efforts.</description></item><item><title>Tenth SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education BPHTE23</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte23_tech_program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte23_tech_program/</guid><description>A workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education (BPHTE23) at SC23</description></item><item><title>Undergraduate Summer Opportunities</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/resources/ugsummerresources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/resources/ugsummerresources/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve assembled a list of summer undergraduate opportunities we&amp;rsquo;re aware of in HPC, computational science, or data science. This list is certainly not complete, so if you know of additional opportunities, please email us at chair at sighpcedu dot com and we&amp;rsquo;ll add it here!
Program: CRA Distributed Research Experiences for Undergraduates (DREU)
Location: Varies
Dates: Summer 2024, students and mentors decide specific dates
Eligibility: Undergrads. Most funds are reserved for US citizens and permanent residents.</description></item><item><title>Workshop Committee</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/committees/workshop/</guid><description>Committee Description The SIGHPC Workshop Committee has its mission promoting the interest in and knowledge of applications of High Performance Computing (HPC) by organizing, coordinating and managing in-person and virtual events and workshops. We are actively engaged in fostering collaborations between all HPC Community members at all education levels in the scientific and big data applications domain, and in facilitating a global forum for HPC and non-HPC members interaction, and in promoting opportunities for members to expand their knowledge of high performance computing.</description></item></channel></rss>