<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Training and Education Resources on AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/resources/</link><description>Recent content in Training and Education Resources on AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://sighpceducation.acm.org/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Computational Science Resources</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/resources/compsciresources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/resources/compsciresources/</guid><description>General Resource Name Type Interactive Science and Math Simulations Web Applets National Science Digital Library Computational Science Education Repository Petasale Education Modules Catalog Repository Petasale Education Modules - Undergraduate Repository Computational Science Education Reference Desk Repository Programming on Parallel Machines Textbook Open Encyclopedia of Parallel Algorithmic Features Textbook Specific Disciplines Resource Type Physics and Math Applets Applets Physics Laboratory Instructions Repository Shodor Model Example &amp;amp; Tools Repository - Chemistry, Biology. Math Economics Agent Models Repository Virtual Physics Laboratory Forum Computational Chemistry for Chemistry Educators Repository</description></item><item><title>HPC Resource Links</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/resources/hpcresources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/resources/hpcresources/</guid><description>Getting Started Resource Name Type Oklahoma University Center for Education and Research Workshops Software Carpentry: Basic Skills for Research Computing Web training Matlab_Octave Tutorial Basics - Supercomputing Portal Repository and Links ARCHER-UK National Supercomputing Service Online Training Repository Everyone Resource Name Type U Illinois Computational Science and Engineering Workshops Software Carpentry - Basic Skills for Research Computing Web Training Data Carpentry Web Training HPC Carpentry Web Training The Art of HPC Web Training MIT LLSC-Supercloud Teaching Examples Hands-on Examples in Jupyter Notebooks HPC Univeristy Training Resources Repository of resources XSEDE Online Training Catalog Repository Novice and Intermediate Resource Name Type MPI Tutorial Tutorial VISIT Visualization Tutorial Tutorial Paraview Visualization Tutorial Tutorial parallel Matlab-parallelOctave Tutorial 2016 Argonne Training Program on Extreme Computing -ATPESC Tutorial Supercomputing Portal -Basics Repository and Links Supercomputing Portal - Development Repository and Links Supercomputing Portal - Debugging Repository and Links Supercomputing Portal - Visualization Repository and Links CINECA-SCAI Online Training Repository CINECA-SCAI Training Slides Repository ARCHER-UK National Supercomputing Service Virtual Tutorials Repository ARCHER-UK National Supercomputing Service Online Training Repository Pawsey Supercomputing Centre User Training Material Repository Petasale Education Modules Catalog Repository Petasale Education Modules - Undergraduate Repository Code Vault for HPC Code Samples Repository Introduction to Visualization Repository Open Encyclopedia of Parallel Algorithmic Features Textbook Intermediate and Advanced Resource Name Type NERSC Online Tutorials Tutorial Large Data Visualization Tutorial HPC Textbook and Parallel Programming Book Book Parallel Programming in MPI and OpenMP Book Programming on Parallel Machines Textbook</description></item><item><title>Systems Professional Resources</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/resources/systems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/resources/systems/</guid><description>The Systems Professionals Committee of the SIGHPC Education Chapter had assembled a list of training resources for systems professionals. In the the future, we also expect to include reviews of the materials. Please provide additional information for this resource listing.
Linux Cluster Institute Oklahoma University Virtual Residency Introductory/Intermediate Workshops Los Alamos National Laboratory Information Science and Technology Institute ISTI</description></item><item><title>Undergraduate Internship and Research Opportunities</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/resources/ugopportunities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/resources/ugopportunities/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve assembled a list of undergraduate opportunities we&amp;rsquo;re aware of in HPC, computational science, or data science. This list is certainly not complete, so if you know of additional opportunities, please email us at chair at sighpcedu dot com and we&amp;rsquo;ll add it here!
Program: Michigan State REU: Advanced Computational Research Experience
Location: East Lansing, MI
Dates: May 20 - July 26, 2024.
Eligiblity: U.S. Citizen or permanent resident.
Applications Due: February 29, 2024.</description></item></channel></rss>