<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Upcoming ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter Committee Events on AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/</link><description>Upcoming events in the ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter committee of the AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SIGHPC Education Annual Meeting 2026 at 9:00 AM EST on Tue, Jan 1, 2026</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/annual26/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/annual26/</guid><description>&lt;p>Please join us for the SIGHPC Education annual meeting on January 13 at 10:00 AM Eastern Standard Time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will review activities completed in 2025, discuss possible new initiatives, and present the scheduled activities for the new year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://us02web.zoom.us/meeting/register/IwcPN5usSRGfGos0MqqCsA">Click here to register&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Educational Award For Outstanding Contribution to Computational Science Education at 9:00 AM EDT on Sun, Mar 3, 2026</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/award26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/award26/</guid><description>&lt;p>The ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter is announcing an upcoming call for nominations for the 2026 education award to recognize outstanding contributions to computational, data-enabled science, and HPC education and training in all disciplines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The call for nominations will be issued in March, 2026 with a deadline for submissions on May 31, 2026.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are seeking candidates who have led projects or programs that have made significant contributions to computational science education defined broadly to include all disciplines and all education levels.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>