<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Upcoming SigHPCEdu Website Committee Events on AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</title><link>https://sighpcedu.github.io/sighpcedu-website/events/</link><description>Upcoming events in the SigHPCEdu Website committee of the AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://sighpcedu.github.io/sighpcedu-website/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Computational Physics Webinar - Computational Physics in the Classroom at 9:00 AM EDT on Wed, Apr 4, 2023</title><link>https://sighpcedu.github.io/sighpcedu-website/events/physicsclass/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 10:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpcedu.github.io/sighpcedu-website/events/physicsclass/</guid><description>Computational Physics Webinar - Computational Physics in the Classroom David Joiner, Rubin Landau, Robert Panoff, Richard Gass
Wednesday, April 5 at 1:00 PM EDT.
Join with zoom
Abstract Presenters will discuss various aspects of integrating computational physics into the classroom
Running classroom 3D Physics simulations with visualization in Unity Game Engine (David Joiner) Some CP Topics that Should be Taught, but Usually Aren&amp;rsquo;t (Rubin Landau) Many Body for Anybody (Robert Panoff) The session will be moderated by Richard Gass</description></item><item><title>HETET23 Call for Papers at 9:00 AM MDT on Thu, May 5, 2023</title><link>https://sighpcedu.github.io/sighpcedu-website/events/hetet23_cfp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpcedu.github.io/sighpcedu-website/events/hetet23_cfp/</guid><description>Call for Papers Workshop on HPC Education and Training for Emerging Technologies (HETET23) ISC23 Conference https://www.isc-hpc.com/
High performance computing has become central for empowering progress in diverse scientific and non-scientific domains. With the advent of myriad different technologies in the post peta-scale computing era, the future of HPC involves a significantly greater degree of parallelism than we are observing currently. The rapid advancement and introduction of new processing technologies for HPC has facilitated the convergence of Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Machine Learning (ML), Data Analytics and Big Data and the High Performance Computing (HPC) domains platforms to solve complex large-scale real-time analytics and scientific applications pertaining to diverse scientific and non-scientific fields.</description></item><item><title>SEHET23 Call for Papers at 9:00 AM MDT on Sun, Jul 7, 2023</title><link>https://sighpcedu.github.io/sighpcedu-website/events/sehet23_cfp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpcedu.github.io/sighpcedu-website/events/sehet23_cfp/</guid><description>SEHET23 Call for Papers PEARC23 Conference Portland, Oregon July 23-27, 2023
https://pearc.acm.org/pearc23/
Sixth Workshop on Strategies for Enhancing HPC Education and Training (SEHET23) The SEHET23 workshop is an ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter coordinated effort aimed at fostering collaborations among the practitioners from traditional and emerging fields to explore strategies to enhance computational, data-enabled and HPC educational needs. Attendees will discuss approaches for developing and deploying HPC training and education, as well as identifying new challenges and opportunities for keeping pace with the rapid pace of technological advances - from collaborative and online learning tools to new HPC platforms.</description></item><item><title>BPHTE23 Call for Papers at 9:00 AM EST on Sun, Nov 11, 2023</title><link>https://sighpcedu.github.io/sighpcedu-website/events/bphte23cfp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpcedu.github.io/sighpcedu-website/events/bphte23cfp/</guid><description>BPHTE23 CFP Call for Papers Tenth SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education (BPHTE23)
November 12-17, 2023
Held in conjunction with SC23: The International Conference on High Performance Computing, Networking, Storage, and Analysis
https://sc23.supercomputing.org/
Since 2014, the Best Practices for HPC Training workshop series at SC has provided a global forum for addressing common challenges and solutions for enhancing HPC training and education, for sharing information through large and small group discussions, and for fostering collaboration opportunities.</description></item></channel></rss>