<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Upcoming ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter Committee Events on AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/</link><description>Upcoming events in the ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter committee of the AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Eighth Workshop on Strategies for Enhancing HPC Education and Training (SEHET25) at 9:00 AM EDT on Mon, Jul 7, 2025</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/sehet25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/sehet25/</guid><description>The SEHET25 workshop is an &lt;a href="https://sighpceducation.acm.org">ACM SIGHPC Education
Chapter&lt;/a> coordinated effort aimed at
fostering collaborations among the practitioners from traditional and
emerging fields to explore strategies to enhance computational,
data-enabled and HPC educational needs. Attendees will discuss
approaches for developing and deploying HPC training and education, as
well as identifying new challenges and opportunities for keeping pace
with the rapid pace of technological advances - from collaborative and
online learning tools to new HPC platforms.</description></item><item><title>CFP: Twelfth SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education (BPHTE25) at 9:00 AM EDT on Tue, Aug 8, 2025</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte25cfp/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte25cfp/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="call-for-papers-twelfth-sc-workshop-on-best-practices-for-hpc-training-and-education-bphte25">Call for Papers Twelfth SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education (BPHTE25)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>November 16-21, 2025 (CFP due August 12, 2025)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Held in conjunction with SC25: The International Conference on High Performance Computing, Networking, Storage, and Analysis&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sc25.supercomputing.org/">https://sc25.supercomputing.org/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since 2014, the Best Practices for HPC Training workshop series at SC has provided a global forum for addressing common challenges and solutions for enhancing HPC training and education, for sharing information through large and small group discussions, and for fostering collaboration opportunities. The Twelfth workshop (BPHTE25), an &lt;a href="https://sighpceducation.acm.org">ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter&lt;/a> coordinated effort, is a full day workshop focusing on extending collaborations among practitioners from traditional and emerging fields, exploring the challenges in developing and deploying HPC training and education, and identifying new challenges and opportunities for the latest HPC platforms. The workshop will provide opportunities for: disseminating results, understanding the recent challenges with effectiveness of HPC education and training materials and promoting collaborations among HPC educators, trainers and users. We are planning for papers, lightning talks and demos to be presented by members of the international community. &lt;em>The workshop papers, extended lightning talks and demo abstracts will be published in a special issue of &lt;a href="http://jocse.org/">Journal of Computational Science Education&lt;/a>&lt;/em> .&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>