<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Upcoming ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter Committee Events on AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/</link><description>Upcoming events in the ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter committee of the AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CFP: Thirteenth SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education (BPHTE26) at 9:00 AM EDT on Wed, Aug 8, 2026</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte26_cfp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte26_cfp/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="call-for-papers">Call for Papers&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="thirteenth-sc-workshop-on-best-practices-for-hpc-training-and-education-bphte26">Thirteenth SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education (BPHTE26)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>November 15-20, 2026&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Held in conjunction with SC26: The International Conference on High Performance Computing, Networking, Storage, and Analysis&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https://sc26.supercomputing.org/__;!!LIr3w8kk_Xxm!rCnZIZNL1ZM0vsDqULsIMUjncqtQvfWPAmK-5q7pzZKxT9ysnnhSu5QeTKMWeUPG2Jzb1oULer1RFbBfjJmoT3g$">https://sc26.supercomputing.org/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since 2014, the Best Practices for HPC Training workshop series at SC has provided a global forum for addressing common challenges and solutions for enhancing HPC training and education, for sharing information through large and small group discussions, and for fostering collaboration opportunities. The Thirteenth workshop (BPHTE26), an &lt;a href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https://sighpceducation.acm.org__;!!LIr3w8kk_Xxm!rCnZIZNL1ZM0vsDqULsIMUjncqtQvfWPAmK-5q7pzZKxT9ysnnhSu5QeTKMWeUPG2Jzb1oULer1RFbBfhcP1-oU$">ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter&lt;/a> coordinated effort, is a full day workshop focusing on extending collaborations among practitioners from traditional and emerging fields, exploring the challenges in developing and deploying HPC training and education, and identifying new challenges and opportunities for the latest HPC platforms.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Educational Award For Outstanding Contribution to Computational Science Education at 9:00 AM EDT on Sun, Mar 3, 2026</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/award26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/award26/</guid><description>&lt;p>The ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter is announcing an upcoming call for nominations for the 2026 education award to recognize outstanding contributions to computational, data-enabled science, and HPC education and training in all disciplines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The call for nominations will be issued in March, 2026 with a deadline for submissions on May 31, 2026.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are seeking candidates who have led projects or programs that have made significant contributions to computational science education defined broadly to include all disciplines and all education levels.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>