<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Upcoming ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter Committee Events on AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/</link><description>Upcoming events in the ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter committee of the AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CodeRefinery at 9:00 AM EDT on Thu, Apr 4, 2024</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/code_refinery/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/code_refinery/</guid><description>SIGHPC Education Webinar CodeRefinery - collaboratively training the next generation of Research Software Engineers CodeRefinery has been teaching over 2500 researchers since 2016 in FAIR research software development practices. All training materials (https://coderefinery.org/lessons/core/) are publicly available for everyone to use for self-learning and reusing (CC-BY) and we offer two free online workshops a year where we try to reach hundreds of participants and dozens of team leaders. The lessons are collaboratively developed with contributions from Nordics and beyond.</description></item><item><title>Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education at 9:00 AM EST on Sun, Nov 11, 2024</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte24cfp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte24cfp/</guid><description>Call for Papers Eleventh SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education (BPHTE24) November 17-22, 2024
Held in conjunction with SC24: The International Conference on High Performance Computing, Networking, Storage, and Analysis
https://sc24.supercomputing.org/
Since 2014, the Best Practices for HPC Training workshop series at SC has provided a global forum for addressing common challenges and solutions for enhancing HPC training and education, for sharing information through large and small group discussions, and for fostering collaboration opportunities.</description></item><item><title>SEHET24 Call for Papers at 9:00 AM EDT on Thu, May 5, 2024</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/sehet24-cfp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/sehet24-cfp/</guid><description>&lt;strong>CALL FOR PAPERS:&lt;/strong> The SEHET24 workshop is an &lt;a href="https://sighpceducation.acm.org">ACM SIGHPC Education
Chapter&lt;/a> coordinated effort aimed at
fostering collaborations among the practitioners from traditional and
emerging fields to explore strategies to enhance computational,
data-enabled and HPC educational needs. Attendees will discuss
approaches for developing and deploying HPC training and education, as
well as identifying new challenges and opportunities for keeping pace
with the rapid pace of technological advances - from collaborative and
online learning tools to new HPC platforms.</description></item><item><title>Nominations Open - Educational Award For Outstanding Contribution to Computational Science Education at 9:00 AM EDT on Fri, Jun 6, 2024</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/award24_nominations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/award24_nominations/</guid><description>The ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter is announcing the initiation of a biannual education award to recognize outstanding contributions to computational, data-enabled science, and HPC education and training in all disciplines. We are seeking nominations for candidates who have led projects or programs that have made significant contributions to computational science education, defined broadly to include all disciplines and all education levels. The executive committee of the SIGHPC Education Chapter (Chair, Vice-chair, and Secretary-treasurer) and SIGHPC are not eligible for this award.</description></item></channel></rss>