<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Upcoming SigHPCEdu Website Committee Events on AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/</link><description>Upcoming events in the SigHPCEdu Website committee of the AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>BPHTE23 Technical Program at 9:00 AM EST on Sat, Nov 11, 2023</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte20_technical_program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte20_technical_program/</guid><description>Tenth SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education BPHTE23 Wednesday November 11, 2020
Time: 10 AM - 6:30 PM (EST)
10:00 PM-10:15 AM
Welcome SIGHPC Education Chapter
Nitin Sukhija, Slippery Rock University of Pennsylvania
10:15 AM -12:00 PM
Session I: (Chair: Scott Lathrop)
10:15 AM -10:30 AM
DeapSECURE Computational Training for Cybersecurity Student: Improvements, Mid-Stage Evaluation, and Lessons Learned. Purwanto, He, Ossom, Zhang, Zhu, Arcaute, Sosonkina, Wu</description></item><item><title>BPHTE23 Call for Papers at 9:00 AM EST on Sun, Nov 11, 2023</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte23cfp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte23cfp/</guid><description>BPHTE23 CFP Call for Papers Tenth SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education (BPHTE23)
November 12-17, 2023
Held in conjunction with SC23: The International Conference on High Performance Computing, Networking, Storage, and Analysis
https://sc23.supercomputing.org/
Since 2014, the Best Practices for HPC Training workshop series at SC has provided a global forum for addressing common challenges and solutions for enhancing HPC training and education, for sharing information through large and small group discussions, and for fostering collaboration opportunities.</description></item><item><title>Tenth SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education BPHTE23 at 9:00 AM EST on Mon, Nov 11, 2023</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte23_tech_program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte23_tech_program/</guid><description>Tenth SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education BPHTE23 Monday November 13, 2023
Time: 2:00 PM - 5:30 PM (MST)
2:00 PM-2:15 P.M
HPC Education Training and Education: Challenges and Opportunities
Nitin Sukhija, Slippery Rock University of Pennsylvania
2:15 PM-3:00 P.M
Paper Session I
2:15 PM-2:30 P.M
Expanding Horizons: Advancing HPC Education in Colombia through CyberColombia&amp;rsquo;s Summer Schools. Carlos Alvarez, Aurelio Vivas, Jose Manuel Monsalve Diaz, Harold Castro, Esteban Hernandez and Juan Lalinde</description></item></channel></rss>