<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Upcoming ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter Committee Events on AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/</link><description>Upcoming events in the ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter committee of the AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education at 9:00 AM EST on Sun, Nov 11, 2024</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte24cfp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte24cfp/</guid><description>Call for Papers Eleventh SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education (BPHTE24) November 17-22, 2024
Held in conjunction with SC24: The International Conference on High Performance Computing, Networking, Storage, and Analysis
https://sc24.supercomputing.org/
Since 2014, the Best Practices for HPC Training workshop series at SC has provided a global forum for addressing common challenges and solutions for enhancing HPC training and education, for sharing information through large and small group discussions, and for fostering collaboration opportunities.</description></item><item><title>Diary of a Pawsey Intern (Mentor) – Panel Discussion at 9:00 AM AWST on Mon, Mar 3, 2024</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/pawseyinternpanel24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/pawseyinternpanel24/</guid><description>Just as Greg muddles his way through middle school in Diary of a Wimpy Kid, Pawsey Interns are asked to navigate a confusing world of science and high performance computing – sometimes with little to no background in either. Join this panel discussion to learn about the 10-week, paid Australian Internship Program as experienced by the Interns and Intern Mentors. Hear their journeys, their challenges and their successes – from bootcamp training through to final project showcase.</description></item><item><title>Nominations Open - Educational Award For Outstanding Contribution to Computational Science Education at 9:00 AM EDT on Fri, Jun 6, 2024</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/award24_nominations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/award24_nominations/</guid><description>Nominations for Educational Award For Outstanding Contribution to Computational Science Education The ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter is announcing the initiation of a biannual education award to recognize outstanding contributions to computational, data-enabled science, and HPC education and training in all disciplines. We are seeking nominations for candidates who have led projects or programs that have made significant contributions to computational science education, defined broadly to include all disciplines and all education levels.</description></item></channel></rss>