<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Upcoming SigHPCEdu Website Committee Events on AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/</link><description>Upcoming events in the SigHPCEdu Website committee of the AMC SIGHPC Education Chapter</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Award 2024 at 9:00 AM EDT on Fri, Mar 3, 2024</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/award24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/award24/</guid><description>Educational Award For Outstanding Contribution to Computational Science Education The ACM SIGHPC Education Chapter is announcing an upcoming call for nominations for the 2024 education award to recognize outstanding contributions to computational, data-enabled science, and HPC education and training in all disciplines.
The call for nominations will be issued in March, 2024 with a deadline for submissions on May 31 2024.
We are seeking candidates who have led projects or programs that have made significant contributions to computational science education defined broadly to include all disciplines and all education levels.</description></item><item><title>Tenth SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education BPHTE23 at 9:00 AM EST on Mon, Nov 11, 2023</title><link>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte23_tech_program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sighpceducation.acm.org/events/bphte23_tech_program/</guid><description>Tenth SC Workshop on Best Practices for HPC Training and Education BPHTE23 Monday November 13, 2023
Time: 2:00 PM - 5:30 PM (MST)
2:00 PM-2:15 P.M
HPC Education Training and Education: Challenges and Opportunities
Nitin Sukhija, Slippery Rock University of Pennsylvania
2:15 PM-3:00 P.M
Paper Session I
2:15 PM-2:30 P.M
Expanding Horizons: Advancing HPC Education in Colombia through CyberColombia&amp;rsquo;s Summer Schools. Carlos Alvarez, Aurelio Vivas, Jose Manuel Monsalve Diaz, Harold Castro, Esteban Hernandez and Juan Lalinde</description></item></channel></rss>